# Nicolás Aldao

#### Frontend Developer with 5 years of experience in IT

⊕ Buenos Aires, Argentina

My Website: nicolas-aldao.vercel.app ☑ nicolasaldao@live.com

in linkedin.com/in/nicolas-aldao 👩 github.com/nicolas-aldao

#### **About me**

I had my first exposure to programming through video games. After studying English for a couple of years, I had the opportunity to begin the System Analyst career, which I completed in 2020. I began my professional journey at an Argentinean IT company, where I worked for 5 years, being part of different kinds of projects, with a focus on Frontend development in my later roles. I find it fascinating to be able to build complex web and mobile applications using creativity and logic to find solutions to people's problems.

## **Work Experience**

## React Developer 2023 - Mar 2024

Baufest | Important bank in Argentina

Fix bugs and new features development in mobile application. Create responsive UI. Deploys with Jenkins. Refactor and optimize old code.

#### **React Native Developer**

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

Baufest | Important bank in Jamaica

Fix bugs and new features development in mobile application. Elaborate unit tests. Fix linting errors. Styled Components

### C# Developer

Baufest | Agribusiness from Argentina

Fix bugs and new features development in application MVC .NET with Razor.

#### **SQL Server and Backend Development Support**

2020 - 2021

Baufest | Agribusiness from Argentina | Oct 2020 - Dic 2021

Fix bugs in application MVC .NET with Razor. Modify and run SQL Scripts.

# BI Tools Support

Baufest | Retail from Latin América

Modify and run Powershell Scripts. Modify and run SQL Scripts. Modify, fix and deploy SQL Data Tools (Integration Services).

## Technical Support 2018 - 2019

Baufest | Important sportswear brand

Control data sellout reports. Automated tasks using Excel and VBA macros. Collaborated with clients via email to resolve daily business problems.

#### **Education & Certifications**

#### React Testing Library with Jest / Vitest course - Udemy

Test-Driven Development. Test behavior instead of implementation

#### Solid and Clean Code principles course - Udemy

Tech Debt. Code Smells. SOLID Principles. Good practices

#### The complete React Native + Hooks course - Udemy

State Management with Context. In-App Authentication. Json Web Token

#### React Native Intensive couse - Baufest

React Intensive Training emulating a real project, building a digital wallet MVP in React to send and receive money. Consuming API's. Form validations.

#### React Courses (various) - Platzi

Local Storage, Session Storage. Webpack, Babel. Lazy loading. PWA's

#### System Analist Career - Instituto Santo Tomás de Aquino

3-year tertiary career at an institute in Argentina. Be able to analize requirements, algoriths and computer systems. Learn and build web pages and desktop applications. Elaborate and apply good practices to relational databases

## **Personal Projects**

## Digital Wallet • O

An app where you can send and receive money from other users. You can also view your transaction history!

React Node MongoodB NextUI

### Artgram • O

Based in Instagram's style in this app you can browse through different art paintings. You can signup, login or use the demo account.

HTML CSS React Node MongoodB

### **Grid Layout Concept** Art: Beatles • O

This is a concept art for a grid layout. I used to The Beatles as an example.

Grid Layout HTML CSS

#### **Skills**



## Languages

Spanish: Native speaker

English: B2

Apr 2024

Apr 2024

Jan 2023

Dec 2022

Jan - Mar 2022

2016 - 2020